dosgames.com 2019-09-29

# DOSGames.com Privacy Policy & Disclaimer

  * Who We Are
  * General Disclaimer
  * What We Collect and Why
  * How Long We Retain your Data
  * How to Access your Data
  * How We Use Cookies
  * Links to Other Websites
  * Force Majeure
  * Privacy Policy Changes
  * Miscellaneous

## Who We Are

Darren Hewer ("the webmaster") operates DOS Games (www.DOSGames.com; "website"). It is the webmaster's policy and desire to respect you ("visitor"), your safety, and your privacy to his best ability.

## General Disclaimer

The DOSGames.com name, graphics, code, reviews, screenshots, and all other related content cannot be re-used without permission from the author(s). All games and other intellectual property referenced on this website remain property of their respective holders, and is used here as part of "fair use". All the information on this website is published in good faith and for entertainment or general information purposes only.

The webmaster disclaims all warranties, expressed or implied, including, and without limitation to, the warranties of merchantability and of fitness for any purpose stated by any game, program, or website, and will not be liable for damages of any kind (direct or consequential) which may result from the use of any program or resource listed, including this website itself and all related content. Any action you take upon the information you find on this website is strictly at your own risk. While we do not knowingly include any malware, viruses, or other harmful components in the website or its files, no guarantee of any kind is provided that this website is safe. Concerned visitors can scan files for safety using free services such as [VirusTotal](https://www.virustotal.com/).

## What We Collect and Why

### Non-personally-identifying information

Such as browser type, language preference, referring site, time and date of visit. The purpose in collecting this sort of information is to better understand how the webmaster's visitors use the website, monitor traffic numbers, and determine ways to improve the visitor's experience. [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/analytics/) is used to collect data of this type; see [Google Analytics Terms of Service](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html).

### Potentially identifying information

Such as IP address. No information of this type is collected at this time except when posting on the Discussion Forum as explained below, or when a visitor chooses to rate a game. Google Analytics has the [IP anonymization](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2763052?hl=en) feature enabled.

### Personally identifying information

Such as name, email address. No visitor is required to provide personally identifying information. Any information entered will be used only for the intended purpose noted below and is not disclosed to other parties, except in the case of third-party services where such use is explicitly mentioned in the privacy policy of that third-party service. The webmaster discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors, and affiliated organizations that need to know that information in order to process it on the webmaster's behalf or to provide services. Some of those employees, contractors, and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using this website, you consent to the transfer of such information to them.

A visitor may choose to voluntarily provide such information when they opt to engage in the following activities:

**Commenting** : Commenting is not currently enabled on DOSGames.com. Previously Facebook Commenting was used.

**Rating games** : When a visitor chooses to rate one of the games on the website, their IP address is stored along with their rating to prevent multiple ratings of the same game. No other personal information is collected from the user or stored at this time.

**Forum** : The [DOSGames.com Discussion Forum](https://dosgames.com/forum/) does not require any registration to post in the "Find Old Games" and "Get Games to Work" forums; only the visitor's IP address is collected when posting anonymously, for security and spam-prevention. Posting in other forums requires voluntary visitor registration including the visitor's email address to prevent spam; the visitor's IP address is also recorded for security and spam-prevention.

**Contact Form** : When contacting the webmaster the visitor is required to enter their name and email address so that the webmaster will know who is writing, and so that they can reply. The visitor's IP address is also recorded for security and spam-prevention.

## How Long We Retain your Data

**Comments** : A comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely, unless removed by the visitor through Facebook's delete functionality. The webmaster also reserves the right, at their sole discretion, to permanently delete comments that are violent, discriminatory, derogatory, promotional, or otherwise unsuitable.

**Rating games** : The visitor's rating and IP address are retained indefinitely, unless removed by the visitor by contacting the webmaster.

**Forum** : A forum account, its metadata, and the visitor's posts are retained indefinitely, unless removed by the visitor. A visitor's forum account including all information above, and optionally any/all of their forum posts, may be permanently deleted from the webserver at any time by contacting the webmaster. The webmaster also reserves the right, at their sole discretion, to permanently delete posts that are violent, discriminatory, derogatory, promotional, or otherwise unsuitable.

**Contact Form** : The visitor's name, email address, IP address, and any other information included in the contact from are never stored on the webserver after completing the contact form. An email is sent to the webmaster including the information entered.

## How to Access your Data

To obtain a copy of the personal information held about you, use the contact form. Please provide sufficient detail about the information in question to help us locate it. If possible we will provide you with the data requested, and aim to do so within a reasonable timeframe.

## How We Use Cookies

Here and hereafter, the terms "cookie" or "cookies" also includes similar browser-based information storage technology such as but not limited to localStorage, sessionStorage, or IndexedDB.

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies, with the drawback that certain features of the website (or other websites) may not function properly.

**To refuse or delete cookies** in your browser, choose your browser below and follow the instructions provided:

**Advertising Cookies** : [Google Adsense](https://www.google.com/adsense/start/#/?modal_active=none) may use cookies to serve ads on this website. Google's possible use of the tracking cookies enables it to serve ads targetted to the visitor. Visitors may opt out of the use of Google's cookie by following the instructions provided here: [Opt out of seeing personalized ads](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en).

**Do Not Track** : This website respects [Do Not Track (DNT)](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Do_Not_Track). If the DNT flag is set in your web browser, the site will attempt to detect this setting, and if found, it will prevent Google Analytics from loading. For more information, including how to set DNT in web browsers, visit [All About Do Not Track](https://allaboutdnt.com/). (Setting the DNT flag will not affect data which is voluntarily provided to the website by the visitor .)

## Links to Other Websites

This website links to other websites which are outside ownership and/or control of the webmaster. No guarantees of safety, security, privacy, or fitness for purpose is made with regard to other websites. While we strive to provide only quality links to useful and ethical websites, we have no control over the content and nature of these sites, which may change at any time. These links to other websites do not imply a recommendation for all the content found on these sites. Visitors who click on outside links are advised to use caution and check the privacy policy of any website they visit.

## Force Majeure

The webmaster will not be liable for any failure to perform our obligations where such failure results from any cause beyond our reasonable control, including, without limitation, mechanical, electronic, environmental, and/or communications problems.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, the webmaster may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, and in the webmaster's sole discretion. Any major changes to this policy will be announced on the main website. However, the webmaster encourages visitors to also check this page for changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such changes.

## Miscellaneous

Last modified: July 4, 2019.

Questions regarding this policy may be addressed to the webmaster here: Contact form.
